[
  {
    "question": "Analyze the following\n\n code:boolean even = false;\n if (even = true)\n {System.out.println(\"It is even!\");\n}",
    "answers": {
      "a": "The program has a compile error.",
      "b": "The program has a runtime error.",
      "c": "The program runs, but displays nothing.",
      "d": "The program runs and displays It is even!"
    },
    "correct": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the Boolean expressions below is correct?",
    "answers": {
      "a": "(true) && (3 => 4)",
      "b": "!(x > 0) && (x > 0)",
      "c": "(x != 0) || (x = 0)",
      "d": "(-10 < x < 0)"
    },
    "correct": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Suppose x=10 and y=10 what is x after evaluating the expression (y > 10) && (x++ > 10).",
    "answers": {
      "a": "9",
      "b": "10",
      "c": "11"
    },
    "correct": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Suppose x=10 and y=10 what is x after evaluating the expression (y >= 10) || (x++ > 10).",
    "answers": {
      "a": "9",
      "b": "10",
      "c": "11"
    },
    "correct": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "The signature of a method consists of __",
    "answers": {
      "a": "method name",
      "b": "method name and parameter list",
      "c": "return type, method name, and parameter list",
      "d": "parameter list"
    },
    "correct": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following class definitions defines a legal abstract class?",
    "answers": {
      "a": " class A { abstract void unfinished() { } }",
      "b": "class A { abstract void unfinished(); }",
      "c": "abstract class A { abstract void unfinished(); }",
      "d": "public class abstract A { abstract void unfinished(); }"
    },
    "correct": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following declares an abstract method in an abstract Java class?",
    "answers": {
      "a": "public abstract method();",
      "b": "public abstract void method();",
      "c": "public abstract void method() {}",
      "d": "public void method() {}"
    },
    "correct": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a correct interface?",
    "answers": {
      "a": "interface A { void print() { }; }",
      "b": "abstract interface A { print(); }",
      "c": "abstract interface A { abstract void print() { };}",
      "d": "interface A { void print();}"
    },
    "correct": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is FALSE about abstract classes in Java",
    "answers": {
      "a": "If we derive an abstract class and do not implement all the abstract methods, then the derived class should also be marked as abstract using 'abstract' keyword",
      "b": "Abstract classes can have constructors",
      "c": "A class can be made abstract without any abstract method",
      "d": "A class can inherit from multiple abstract classes."
    },
    "correct": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is FALSE about arrays on Java",
    "answers": {
      "a": "A java array is always an object",
      "b": "Length of array can be changed after creation of array",
      "c": "Arrays in Java are always allocated on heap"
    },
    "correct": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Java, when we implement an interface method, it must be declared as:",
    "answers": {
      "a": "Private",
      "b": "Protected",
      "c": "Public",
      "d": "Friend"
    },
    "correct": "c"
  }
]
